# Celian **RINGWALD** Phd Student at INRIA, 3IA, CNRS, I3S, Université Côte d'Azur

23 avenue bellevue 06100 Nice, France celian.ringwald@inria.fr +(33) 766600029

github.com/datalogism

**y** @ringwald\_c

in linkedin.com/in/ringwaldcelian

Since dec. 2022, I'm working as Phd Student on the following research question: How to learning RDF pattern extractors for a given language from dual bases Wikipedia/Linked Open Data.

Keywords: Semantic web, Knowledge graphs, NLP, Computational Linguistics, Deep Learning

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 1 year 2 months

# R&D Engineer in charge of DBpedia Fr, WIMMICS TEAM, Inria Sophia-Antipolis

Oct. 2021 - Nov. 2022

- under the supervision of Fabien Gandon and Franck Michel
  > Update of the french chapter (new software pipeline, website and documentation update)
- > New extractors development : Historic, DBpedia Abstracts extraction.
- > Data enrichment : Wikidata integration, meta description, data fusion
- > New research projects: Wikipedia article relations extraction, DBpédia Spotlight upgrading for French

#### 6 months

## Mathematics teacher, COLLÈGE JEAN PERRIN, Lyon

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2021

Substitute teacher in a secondary school

#### 6 months

# Datascientist Freelance, DATARTISAN, Lyon

Sept. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Datascience and NLP R&D missions

#### 6 months

#### [Intern] Research assistant, DIGITAL HUMANITIES CANADA RESEARCH CHAIR, Ottawa

Mar. 2020 - Aug. 2020

under the supervision of Sabine Loudcher & Constance Crompton:

TEI corpus transformation workflow to Linked Open Data format, Ontological modeling for historical and cultural shared knowledge base.

The Entity Linking tutorials.

Master Thesis on biographic extraction relation for prosopography semantic-based representations.

## 3 years

## Datascientist, DATA OBSERVER, Marseille

Feb. 2017 - Feb. 2020

Software development, Data visualization, TAL/ML pipelines, involved into:

- > ExObserver : A multilingual platform for social listening, with annotation and corpus analysis tools
- > SourceBase: Taxonomy of media sources, shared mediametry database of media sources.
- > MedObserver: multilingual bibliometric and social extraction tools for specialists and experts of medical domain spotting.
- > Sprayz: Citation and propagation analysis dashboard system for cross media diffusion evaluation.
- > Dortl: Concordance interface, Dynamic Iramuteq PCA like interface, media domain and specialized lexicons.
- > tailor-made projects : Quote extraction project, causality tagging, Controversy maps, Crawl engineering.

#### 6 months

## [Intern] Datascientist, RÉUNIWATT, Réunion Island

Mar. 2016 - Aug. 2016

Econometric, Machine learning and Deep learning models bootstrapping and stacking for photovoltaic production forecasting.

> under the supervision of Ricco Rakotomalala.

#### 6 months

## [Intern] Software Engineer, CENTRE INFORMATIQUE DE PHILOSOPHIE ET LETTRES, Liège

Mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

under the supervision of Julien Ah-Pine

**□** Java embedded software for poetic archive mining.

#### 5 months

## [Intern] Statistical analyst, ARTECA, Nancy

Mar. 2014 - Aug. 2014

under the supervision of Julien Ah-Pine

Analysis of the public culture funding, comparisons of regions with a focus on the live entertainment question.

# **EDUCATION**

2018-2020	Master 2 HN - Master of Digital Humanities - Lyon University (with highest honour)
2014-2016	Master 2 SISE - Master of Datascience - Lyon University (with high honours)
	> Erasmus : 6 months (september - décember 2015)
	Poznan University of Technology : Software Engineering Program
2013-2014	Licence IDS - Bachelor of IT and statistics - Lyon University
2011-2013	DUT STID - Two-year university degree of IT and Statistics Lorraine University
2010-2011	DUT TC - Two-year university degree in Marketing (not completed) - Lorraine University
2010	BAC S - Scientific baccalaureate - Lycée André Malraux

# SEMINARS PARTICIPATION AT NATIONAL CONFERENCES

	Matthias Gille Levenson, Sofia Papastamkou & Célian Ringwald, Programming Historian : un lieu de colla-
June 2022	borations et d'interactions multiples, DHNord 2022 : Travailler en humanités numériques : collaborations,
	complémentarités et tensions, Lille, France. 🖹

- 2022 Célian Ringwald, Marie-Véronique Leroi, Thibault Grouas, Fabien Gandon, Franck Michel. Présentation du projet DBpedia en français dans le cadre de la convention Culture-Inria. 🖹 🖸
- Anaïs Chambat, Inès Burri, Célian Ringwald. Faire émerger le réseau littéraire francophone haïtien à l'ère du numérique. Séminaire du groupe Approches Sociales et Historiques des Littératures des Suds.
- Anaïs Chambat, Inès Burri, Célian Ringwald. Ébauche de visualisation des productions littéraires francophones d'Haïti et retour d'expérience. In : Cartographie du web littéraire francophone.

# SIDE PROJECTS PARTICIPATIONS

28/29 Oct. 2022	ISSA Hackaton participation with Benjamin Molinet - Development of tools for Archive mining: Embedding
	networks computation - Multi-labels specificity computation 🗁
May-Sept. 2022	Google Summer of Code project - mentored by Mykola Medynskyi & Marvin Hofer & Dimitris Kontokostas,
	6 months project on the Wikipedia abstracts extractors development for solving large scale issues. New API
	integration, NIF text extractor update, MediaWiki docker of a Wikipedia chapter. 🖹
Since Jan. 2021	Volunteer Editor for the Programming Historian Peer-reviewed and open source academic journal about
	digital humanities and digital methodology for social sciences and history. (Proofreading, Article transla-
	tion &Reviewing French proposals)

# Technical and Scientifics skills

Mathematics Statistics, Algebra, Probabilities, Optimization, Logic, Graph theory, Time Series

Java, C, Scala, Python, Javascript, R, SAS, SPARQL

Relational, Key-values db, Oriented documents and graph db

Machine learning, Deep learning methods, Webscrapping, Big Data technologies

NLP Machine learning, Stochastic models, Rule based models, Embedding models.

Social Sciences Hilosophy of language, Linguistic theory, Media theory, Sociology, Digital anthropology







- > Music (Guitar / Accordion)
- > Graphic arts (Ink & watercolor painting / wood craving)
- ➤ Reading (Fantastic / Surealism / S.F.)
- > Sports (Tennis / Skate)